（戦車隊長）
フン！ 小うるさいハエが
Annoying fly...
（戦車隊長）
このわし自ら 葬ってくれるわ
I'll bury him myself!
（信(しん)）騎馬の機動力
そして この鉄の槍なら… いける！
With the mobility of the horse...
and this iron pole... I can do it!
お前らに用はねえ
I'm not interested in you guys!
俺の相手は―
My opponent is...
ムカつく戦車そのものだ！
this shitty chariot, itself!
Now the counterattack begins!
反撃開始だ！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
Timing
G_I_A
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
Typesetting
rtrs
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I knew at the start that there's no end.
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
A Blazing Battle
Xin!
（尾平(びへい)）信！
（信）おう！
Thanks!
そうか ほかが
全滅してたわけじゃねえんだ　よし
Oh, man! The others weren't all wiped out!
Okay!
よく生きていた！
それでこそ秦国の勇敢なる戦士たち
Good work staying alive!
That's why you're the brave warriors of the State of Qin!
Over that way, fresh warriors are gathering and fighting a tough battle!
向こうで 生きのいいヤツらが
固まって奮闘している
全員 急いで合流し 一緒に戦え！
All of you, hurry and join them in their fight!
（田有(でんゆう)）ははっ！
して 騎兵どのは どこへ？
Okay!
Where are you going, mounted soldier?
I'm gonna take down that one chariot that got away and catch up with you!
俺は 逃げた１台を討って合流する
いいか？
Got that? We haven't lost yet!
俺たちは まだ負けちゃいねえ
勝負は これからだ！
The real fight's just beginning!
よし 友軍に合流するぞ
ケガ人には肩貸してやれ
Okay! Let's go join our allies.
Lend a shoulder to the wounded!
Hey, Tian You,
（中鉄(ちゅうてつ)）おい 田有 今の騎兵どの
甲冑(かっちゅう)じゃなくてボロ服だったぞ
that mounted soldier wasn't wearing any armor, just tattered clothes.
うん？ そういえば
あのうるさいガキに似てたような…
Now that you mention it, he looked a lot like that loud-mouth brat from before...
What in the world is going on?
何が どうなってんだ？ 一体
Our loss of foot soldiers has been too dramatic.
（壁(へき)）歩兵の消耗が激しすぎる
（壁）全ての兵を
無駄死にさせるようなこの戦い方で
Do you intend to defeat Wei using this strategy where all of our soldiers die meaninglessly?!
魏(ぎ)を討てるというのか？
（縛虎申(ばくこしん)）無駄死にではない
（壁）ハッ…
They were not meaningless deaths!
They were honorable deaths in battle made for the sake of victory!
（縛虎申）
勝利のための栄誉ある戦死だ
縛虎申…
Fu Hushen, how is it you can be so sure of victory in this situation?
（壁）お前は
なぜ この状況で勝利を疑わない？
麃公(ひょうこう)とは それほど信に足る将か？
Is Biao Gong really a reliable general?
I know no man as strong a general of war as him.
あの方ほど戦に強い将を
俺は ほかに知らぬ
At this time, the main army of the Wei Chariot Corps that attacked Xin and the 4th Army
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
このとき 信たち第４歩兵を
襲った魏国戦車隊本陣は―
continued onward, attacking the 2nd and 1st Armies in one-sided offensives.
そのまま 第２軍 第１軍を襲い
一方的な攻勢を奮っていた
秦国と魏国の戦力比は―
With the ratio of military capability between the Qin and Wei
もはや戦局を決定づけたと言っても
過言ではなかった
it would not be unreasonable to say the course of the war was decided.
Xin
4th Army
信たちの活躍も
戦車大隊の１小隊を討ったにすぎず
Xin's actions only resulted in the defeat of one platoon.
極めて局所的なものだ
It was a very local victory.
Gong Yuan
大局に
何ら影響を与えてはいなかったのだ
It had no effect on the large scale.
（宮元(きゅうげん)）もはや秦軍には
あらがう力など残っておらぬ
The Qin Army already lacks the power to oppose us!
本軍守備を残し 全軍で丘を下り
敵愚将 麃公の首を取るべし！
Main army, leave the defensive! All units, descend the mountain
and take the foolish enemy general Biao Gong's head!
Gong Yuan
Xin
Wei Vice General, Gong Yuan, grew impatient among the momentum
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）魏副将 宮元は―
and did not even recognize Xin and the other's pebble-like resistance.
大流の中で もがく小石のごとき
信たちの抵抗を―
認識すらしなかった
大局の動きだす足音に―
In the sound of the entire larger army's footsteps,
the cheers over Xin and the other's victory seemed to be erased.
信たちの勝利の歓声は
むなしく かき消されるかに見えた
ところが…
However...
（麃公）ほほう…
第４歩兵の一部が 戦車を倒した？
So a section of the 4th's soldiers defeated some chariots?
（連絡将校１）
…が しかし 敵の反撃は時間の問題
Yes, but,
the enemy's counterattack is just a matter of time.
Gong Yuan's main army has begun to move.
宮元の主軍が動きました
ここは ひとまず―
So now, we await your orders!
退避を…
見てみよ
（連絡将校１）は… はい
Look here.
S-Sir?
The solders at each location may seem to be fighting the same way,
（麃公）各地で同じように
戦っているように見えるが
but they actually sway the board in varying ways.
それぞれは
実に多様に 盤上を揺り動かす
ひとつの動きが十を動かし
千につながり 万を崩す
The movement of one moves ten.
And along with a thousand, ten thousand will crumble.
A chain reaction that starts small calls forth a great flame
小から始まる連鎖が大火を呼び込み
戦局は 一気に終局に向かう
and bring the war towards the endgame all at once.
And now, one location has stood out.
そして今 異彩を放つ場所があった
そういう所には何かがある
There is a certain something in those sorts of places...
That is the way of war.
戦とは そういうものじゃ
のう？ 皆の者
Don't you think, everyone?
第４軍 全騎馬兵に
突撃の号令じゃ！
I order all mounted soldiers of the 4th Army to charge!
突撃ーっ！
Charge!
H-Hey!
（尾平）お… おい！
It's the mounted soldiers...
騎馬兵だ！
They finally... They finally came, dammit!
（尾到(びとう)）やっと…
やっと来やがった ちくしょうめ！
We're saved!
（尾到）助かった…
（尾平）生き延びた！
We're gonna live!
（魏兵たち）ウワッ…
ウオーッ！
（信）壁のあんちゃん！
Brother Bi!
（壁）信！ よくぞ無事だった
Xin! Good job staying safe!
I see...
なるほど
The one who prompted General Biao Gong to move was them, was it...?
麃公将軍を動かしたのは
こいつらか
（壁）円陣旋回にて蹂躙(じゅうりん)しろ！
Form a circle around them and overrun them!
Foot soldiers, spread that defensive wall to the right!
歩兵は
その防壁を右に広げて備えよ
Eventually, the main unit of the chariot corps will return!
そのうち
戦車隊本隊が引き返してくるぞ！
He's too damn honest for a central Thousand Man General.
生真面目な中央の千人将め
頭の回転は速いようだな
Though he does appear to think quickly...
だが 騎馬隊突撃の意味が
分かっては いないな
Still, he does not understand the reason behind the charge of the mounted units.
The general's true intentions are about to overturn everything.
将軍の本意は
ここから大局を覆すことだ
縛虎申隊歩兵 整列！
Fu Hushen Unit foot soldiers, line up!
よくぞ
魏軍戦車の攻撃から生き延びた
Well done, surviving the Wei Army chariots' attack.
And beyond that, to have launched a counterattack,
そのうえで 反撃にまで出たことは
縛虎申隊の誇りであり
秦国の誇りである！
you are the pride of the Fu Hushen Unit and the pride of the State of Qin!
You, men who have overcome a desperate struggle from the jaws of death,
絶体絶命の死地を
乗り越えた貴様らならば―
更なる死地をも乗り越えられる！
（歩兵たち）ええっ！
you are surely able to survive a further bout with death!
これより我が隊は
敵歩兵隊中央を強行突破し
My unit will now force our way through to the center of the enemy soldiers
and take the head of the Wei Vice General, Gong Yuan, that sits atop the hill!
丘頂上の魏副将 宮元の首を取る！
突撃態勢！
歩兵は 騎馬の後ろに続け！
Get in charging formation!
All foot soldiers, follow the mounted units!
If you don't want to die, go with all your strength!
死にたくなければ
全力でついてこい！
H-Hold on a second.
ちょっと待ってくれよ… せっかく
騎馬が来て 助かったと思ったのに
When those horses showed up I thought we were safe!
Why do we have to go do another insane battle?!
なんで また そんなムチャ
しなくちゃなんねえんだよ…
Our unit that had 1,000 men doesn't even have 100 now...
（尾到）
1,000人いた隊が 今や100人足らず
あんな万にも上る大軍を―
Around 100 men can't make it through a huge army of 10,000 men...
100人や そこらで
抜けられるわけねえ
いや そうとも限んねえぞ
Not necessarily.
どういうこった？ 信
何か見込みがあんのか？
What're you talking about, Xin?!
Do you think we have a chance?!
えっ？ いや まあ… なんとなく
（尾平）何じゃ そりゃ…
Uh, well... I'm just saying.
What the hell?!
It's as Xin says. There is a chance.
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）
信の言うとおり見込みはある
（羌瘣）丘を下ってくる勢いに
任せた敵の行動は速い
Relying on the momentum gained from going down the hill, the enemy is fast.
その波を逆に突き進むのは
想像を絶する過酷な道
For us to push in the opposite direction of that wave
would be an unimaginably rigorous path.
But in exchange for that, the times for crossing swords will be short.
（羌瘣）
だが その分 斬り結ぶ時間は短い
そうそう それそれ
ヤツらを抜けりゃ―
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
If we get through them
ガラ空きの丘を駆け上がって
一気に敵副将を討てる
and run up the then empty hill, we can take down the enemy vice general in one shot!
そうすりゃ
この戦は こっちのもんだ！
If we can do that, this battle's ours!
ただ さっきも言ったとおり
過酷な道だぞ
It's just as I said, a rigorous path.
立ち止まれば
確実に 死が待っている
If we stop, death will be awaiting us.
ヘッ… どうしたよ？ お前
戦車の辺りから―
What's with you?
Ever since the chariots showed up
やけに
しゃべるようになったじゃねえか
you've been talkin' quite a bit, haven't ya?
I thought you said you hated talking?
話すのが嫌いとか言っといてよ
（羌瘣）お前と同じだ
（信）えっ？
I'm just the same a you.
こんな所で死ぬわけには いかない
I cannot to die in a place like this.
へえ… そうかよ
Is that right?
だが これで決まったな
敵は 俺が蹴散らしてやる
Well then it's decided.
I'll kick around the enemy!
よし 突撃態勢だ！
（尾平）お前が言うな バカ！
Okay, get in charging formation!
You're not the one who gets to say that, Moron!
（部下）
縛虎申さま 歩兵のぶんざいで―
Lord Fu Hushen, there's someone at the rank of foot soldier riding a horse...
騎馬した者がおりますが
（縛虎申）放っておけ
Leave him be.
恐らく
あの残党を引っ張ってきたのは―
Most likely, the one leading those remnants is that kid.
あのガキだ
何かの折に 役に立つだろう
He may serve a purpose by some chance...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
このとき前線では４万の魏軍が―
At this time, the 40,000 Wei Army soldiers on the front lines
僅か1,000人程度の秦軍の騎馬隊に
苦戦を強いられていた
are forcing the mere 1,000 mounted units of the Qin Army into a hard fight.
麃公の命による急襲が
功を奏したのである
The attack ordered by Biao Gong yielded results.
（連絡将校２）
しかし あの数では そのうちに
押し返されると思われます
But against those numbers, it's believed they'll be pushed back.
（連絡将校１）急報！ 敵戦車隊が
第４軍を再び狙っております！
Urgent report! The enemy chariot corps are once again targeting the 4th Army!
第１軍 第２軍騎馬隊に号令！
Issue this order to the 1st and 2nd Army Mounted Units.
第４軍 合戦場へ突撃じゃ！
Charge for the 4th Army's battleground!
Having personal experience in setting foot on critical battlegrounds, Biao Gong quickly adapted to the situation.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）ここが戦の正念場と
踏んだ麃公の素早い対応であった
Go!
行け行け！ 立ち止まるな！
Don't stop moving!
何をやっとるのだ？ あの隊は
深く入り過ぎだ
What's that unit doing?!
They've gone in too deep!
（尚鹿(しょうかく)）縛虎申だ
It's Fu Hushen!
He's probably breaking through to the center to try to get the hill!
恐らく
中央突破して丘を狙うのだろう
（壁）
バカな　半分も行かずに全滅するぞ
That's insane!
He'll be wiped out before he gets half way!
ハハッ…
死に急ぐヤツは放っておけ
You should leave people who rush to their death alone.
I can't do that!
そうは いかない
Bi Unit!
壁隊！
錐行(すいこう)隊列で 奥深くまで斬り込め！
Create a triangular formation and cut into the center!
縛虎申隊の進行を援護しろ！
Back up the Fu Hushen's advance!
ハアーッ！
大丈夫か？ 澤(たく)さん
You okay, Mr. Ze?!
I-I'm okay! Somehow!
（澤圭(たくけい)）だ… 大丈夫です なんとか
You leading us is really saving us, Young Xin!
信君が先導してくれるんで
助かります
Dammit! Thousand Man General Fu Hushen is flying to far ahead!
（尾到）ちくしょう！
縛虎申千人将 飛ばし過ぎだ！
What does he think we foot soldiers are?!
俺たち歩兵を何だと思ってやがる！
はなっから
歩兵のことなんか考えちゃいねえよ
He hasn't been thinking about the foot soldiers at all from the beginning!
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
到 大丈夫か？
（尾到）大丈夫だ…
Dao, are you okay?!
I'm fine!
走れ　とにかく走り抜けて…
Run! We've just gotta run though here...
Big Brooooo!
兄貴ーっ！
（魏兵たち）ウワーッ！
お前…
You...
尾平さん 早く！
Wei Ping, hurry, get up!
立って！ 急がないと 完全に
敵の中に取り残されてしまいます！
If you don't hurry, we'll be left among the enemy!
大丈夫だ　俺が切り開く！
It's okay! I'll cut our way through!
信！
（澤圭）信君！
Xin!
Young Xin!
俺たちの千人将に追いつくぞ！
I'll catch up to our Thousand Man General!
Don't trip up again, Wei Ping!
もう ずっこけんなよ 尾平！
（尾平）お… おう
R-Right!
ヤッ！ ンンッ！
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
Qiang Lei...
羌瘣…
I thought he was just a pretty sharp guy, but he knows how to handle a sword, too...
ただのキレるヤツかと思ってたが
剣も相当に使う
Bastard. Hiding all this from us...
野郎 何か いろいろ隠してやがんな
まあいい
Well, whatever.
これで 後ろを気にせず
前だけに集中できそうだ！
Now I don't need to worry about the back of the group,
and I can concentrate only on the front!
（縛虎申）ウリャー！
デヤーッ！
デヤッ！ ンンッ！ ヤッ！
（縛虎申）
どうした？ 魏兵　その程度か？
What's wrong, Wei soldiers?
Is this all you have?
勝つためなら
俺は全てを くれてやるぞ！
For the sake of winning, I'll give you everything!
（山和(さんか)）ぬ… 抜けた
W-We made it through...
（縛虎申）中腹にいる守備隊
こちらに気づいていない
There are garrisons on the mountainside.
They haven't realized we're here.
How many men are left?
何人 残った？
（部下）40人程度です
About 40.
そうか
（信）ちょっと待ってくれよ
I see...
Hang on a second.
５人足して45人程度だ
Add 5 to that, we've got 45 people.
本隊から遅れたにもかかわらず―
Despite that they separated from our main unit
死地を切り抜けてきたというのか
この小僧…
he escaped the jaws of death?
This kid...
これより 丘を駆け上がり
副将 宮元を討つ！
We'll now run up this hill
and attack Vice General Gong Yuan!
この一戦 秦軍の勝利そのものに
関わる大事と心得よ！
Know well that this battle will be linked directly to the Qin Army's victory itself!
貴様らに
もはや 余力がないことは承知だ
I'm aware that you all no longer have any spare strength left!
しかし 甘えは許さん！
（歩兵たち）ええっ…
But I will not tolerate dependency!
頂上まで来なかった者は
あとで 俺が斬る！ だが―
Those who do not come to the peak will be later cut down by me personally!
But... those who do come to the peak
頂上まで来た者は こたびの戦
最大の功労者としての―
will gain the honor of being the most commendable people in this battle.
栄誉を手にできる　そして―
As well as a reward!
恩賞もだ
（歩兵たち）オオッ…
丘上(きゅうじょう)に陣取ってるのは
魏の高級武官たちだ
The ones camped at the peak of this hill are Wei's top-class officers.
しかも
ヤツらの首の価値は 限りなく高い
And the value of taking their heads is exceedingly high as well...
ふだんの10倍の恩賞を約束してやる
I promise 10 times the normal reward!
兄貴
俺たち 村の英雄になれるかもだぜ
Big Brother, we could become heroes of the village.
ああ こうなりゃ やるっきゃねえな
Now I kinda feel like I can do it.
Hey, kid.
（縛虎申）おい 小僧
（信）えっ？
Leave your Wu and take the lead.
貴様は 伍(ご)を離れ 先頭に来い
（信）えっ…
Even if it's just one more, now's the time we need horses.
今は １騎でも騎馬が必要だ
All righ-
やった！ あっ…
でも そうしたら 澤さんたちが…
Ah, but then what about Mr. Ze and the others...
（尾平）バカ 行けよ 信
You idiot. Just go, Xin.
今更
俺たちのことなんか気にすんな
Don't be worrying about us at a time like this.
信君が伍に収まらないことは
十分 承知しました
We're well aware you're beyond the scope of this Wu.
天下の大将軍になるんだろう？
You're gonna become the greatest general under the heavens, right?
誰よりも でっかい功を上げろよ 信
Go get a bigger achievement than anyone else, Xin!
This is good dust...
（縛虎申）いい砂塵(さじん)だ
起伏の陰に入れば気づかれん
If we can get into the shadows of the clouds, they won't notice us.
全員に気配を消すことを徹底させろ
（部下）はっ！
Tell everyone to hide their presence and make it through.
Yes, sir.
Kid.
小僧
（信）うん？
でかい手柄が欲しいか？
Do you want big achievements?
Of course.
もちろん
Then keep cutting through without ever turning back.
ならば
振り返らずに ひたすら斬り進め
うん？
あっ！ な… 何なんだ？ お前
Wh-What're you doing?!
しばらく乗せろ
（信）なんだと？
Let me ride for a while.
What?!
出るみたいだぞ
（信）おい 人の話 聞けよ
It looks like we're leaving.
Hey, listen to people when they talk.
Fu Hushen Unit, sortie!
縛虎申隊 出撃
どういうつもりだ？
あっ… てめえ 便乗して―
So what're you up to with this?
Are you trying to take advantage and get some achievements for your-
手柄 横取りしようってんじゃ…
（小突く音）
何だ？
（信）な… 何でもねえ
What is it?
N-Nothing!
（馬のいななき）
ウワッ！
気をつけろ
（信）るっせえ
Be careful.
Sheddep.
（壁）ハアーッ！
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
What in the world is going on inside those dust clouds?
（守備隊長）あの砂塵の中
一体 何が起きているのか…
Regardless, our army's numbers are overwhelming.
（守備隊長）
だが 我が軍の兵の数は圧倒的
No matter what happens, the state of the battle will not change.
何が起ころうと 戦局は変わらぬ
It looks like in the end, the capabilities of the generals were too different.
結局 将の力量が違い過ぎた
The result of this battle was determined from the outset.
この戦いの勝敗は
最初から決まっていたのだ
Before long this dust will settle and the Qin soldiers will all die out.
程なく この砂塵は収まり
秦兵は 死に絶えるだろう
これが
“虎狼(ころう)の国”といわれる秦の実力か
Is this the strength of the Qin, the place known as the kingdom of wild beasts?
拍子抜けも いいところ…
What a disappointment.
Enemy attack!
敵襲！
（斬る音）
（魏兵）敵襲！ 敵襲だ！
Enemy attack!
It's an enemy attack!
There are more guys here than I expected!
こいつら 思ってたより多い
（縛虎申）数に惑わされるな！
Don't be distracted by their numbers!
突破が目的だ
各自 10人斬れば抜ける
Our goal is to break through!
If each of us cuts down ten people, we can get through!
なるほど！
Got it!
（副官）宮元さまに報告
A report, Lord Gong Yuan.
中腹の守備隊が
秦の小隊と戦っております
The garrisons on the side of the hill are fighting with a small Qin unit.
Call Huang Li Xian.
黄離弦(こうりげん)を呼べ
（黄離弦）ここに
I'm here.
（黄離弦）お任せを
Leave it to me.
くそ！
１人10人どころじゃ済まねえ！
Shit!
Ten guys for each of us won't be nearly enough!
後ろは任せろ
Leave the back to me!
（羌瘣）行け　止まるな！
（歩兵たち）お… おう！
Go! Don't stop!
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
（守備兵１）うん？ どうした？
追え！ あのガキか？
Huh? What's wrong?
Follow them. Who's that brat?!
（守備兵２）左右から挟み込め
逃げ場をなくすんだ！
Form a pincer from the left and the right!
Leave them nowhere to escape!
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
（守備兵１）
バ… バカな　何だ？ このガキは
I-Impossible!
What is this kid?!
He's quick.
すばしっこいな　もう一度 行くぞ
（守備兵２）ちょっと待て　侮るな
Let's go at him again!
Hold on. Don't underestimate him.
（守備兵１･２）あっ…
トーンタンタン トーンタンタン…
トーンタンタン トーンタンタン
何言ってる？
（守備兵１）分からん
What's he saying?
I dunno.
トーンタンタン トーンタンタン
We got through!
（信）抜けた！
We'll now cut away from the foot soldiers!
ここで歩兵を切り離す
騎馬隊 全力前進！
Mounted unit, move forward with all your might!
えっ… ちょっと待ってくれ
騎馬隊の援護がなきゃ後ろの連中が
Hold on a second!
Without the mounted unit as backup, the guys in the back will...
まさか…
No way!
From the beginning, you brought them in order
後ろの時間を稼ぐために 初めから
そのつもりで連れてきたのか？
to buy time with the guys behind us?!
Didn't I tell you not to turn back?!
後ろを振り向くなと言ったはずだ！
（信）だけど…
But...!
The vanguard, the rear guard, the mounted units and the foot soldiers
先陣も後陣も 騎馬も歩兵も
ひとしく 死線の上にいる
all equally stand at the verge of life and death.
全ては勝利のために
それが軍というものだ！
Everything is for the sake of victory.
That is the nature of an army!
And we have no time to be worrying about others!
（縛虎申）それに
他人の心配をしている暇はないぞ
先陣には 常に
最も過酷な道が用意されている
The vanguard always have the most severe path in front of them!
アアッ… 頑張れ！
今は お前の脚に懸かってる
Hang in there!
I'm counting on your legs right now!
（部下）見ろ！ 頂上が すぐそこ…
（矢の刺さる音）
Look! The peak is just ahea-
There's a bowman unit!
弓隊がいるぞ！
散れ！
Disperse!
マジかよ！
For real?!
ンンッ… くそ！
Shit!
放て！
Fire!
（縛虎申）連弩(れんど)隊か
A repeating crossbow unit, huh?!
兵法家風情が好みそうな
最終防衛だ
A final defense of a real strategist.
だが矢ごときに何本うがたれようが
痛みすら感じぬわ！
But no matter how many arrows I may be pierced with,
I cannot even feel pain!
All units, don't falter!
全軍 ひるむな！
頂上は すぐそこだ！
The peak is right before us!
あいつが将か
So he's the general?
Wait!
待て　俺の獲物だ
He's my prey.
Don't get conceited
（宮元）
思い上がるな 秦の特攻兵ども
suicide attack soldiers of Qin...
Do you think you the state of a battle of tens of thousands can be changed with just a few dozen men?
僅か数十人で
万の大局を変えられるものか
A war is not such a cheap thing!
戦は そんなに易(やす)くない！
フン…
あっ… お待ちを 黄離弦さま
（黄離弦）うん？
Wait! Lord Huang Li Xian!
ほう…
だが脳天を射ぬいても笑えるかな？
But will you still be able to laugh with one shot through your crown?
てめえ！ ぶっ殺す！
You bastard, I'll kill you!
ハアーッ！
少年兵？ 哀れな
秦は そこまで兵不足か
A boy soldier? How pitiful.
Is Qin that short on men?
But an enemy is an enemy.
だが 敵は敵　全力で射殺す
I'll shoot them dead with all my power!
なに？ バカな！
What? Impossible!
俺の矢が見えたのか？
He saw my arrow?
ならば確実に しとめてやろう
Then I'll make sure to take you down...
（信）本陣まで あと少し
It's just a little further to the main camp.
しかし近すぎる　見切れねえ！
But he's too close!
I can't see his shot all!
悪く思うな 小僧
Don't think badly of me, kid.
だが 急所さえ外せば 剣が届く！
But as long as he misses my vitals, my sword will reach him!
The one to win will be me!
（黄離弦）勝つのは俺だ！
ウワッ…
届かなかったな 小僧
You didn't make it, kid.
これが戦だ！
This is war!
ハアーッ！
（縛虎申）やっと会えたな 宮元
So we finally meet, Gong Yuan!
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
～♪
Preview
That General Wang Qi showed up.
（壁）あの王騎(おうき)将軍が現れた
何かが起こる…
What's gonna happen?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）予測不能の闖入者(ちんにゅうしゃ)
不敵な笑みが 戦場を揺るがす
An unpredictable intruder.
A fearless smile shakes the battlefield!
Wang Qi Intrudes
End
Next time,
次回 “王騎乱入”